Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Operation Odessa ended in
victory for the Earth Federation.
As a result, the Zeon forces
were driven back from Europe...
And now the war was
proceeding in a new direction.
Char Returns
Ready, Gunperry?
Docking searcher, 5, 4, 3...
Go ahead with the B Parts.
Core change! Docking, go!
Amuro! What do you think you're doing?
You still haven't broken
the 17 second mark in docking!
You're asking the impossible.
The Core Fighter was meant to be
an escape capsule for the Gundam.
It's quick to get out, but not to get back in.
It may seem impossible,
but Amuro can do it.
The White Base is headed for a Federation
supply base in Northern Ireland...
...to repair damage incurred at
the battle for Odessa.
Yes, I finally have a chance to cut loose
and relax for once.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Why?
Our destination is
a Federation Forces dock, right?
It means we're officially part of the military.
Who knows what we may be
ordered to do from now on.
Is that right?
That certainly took the fun out of it.
I've never seen that type of warship before.
Unknown warship entering Dock 2.
Type unclear.
Sir. We've been contacted by No. 107.
We'd better inform the captain about this.
We have a report from No. 107...
...that a large warship has entered SR4.
This picture is useless.
There's just too much radio interference.
Show me.
Hm. I can't make it out.
Isn't Boone's team
stationed in this area?
Yes, sir!
Get the Sealance ready!
As soon as we've checked the surface,
bring up the Mad Angler.
You could just order
Boone to deal with it.
No, if it's the Trojan Horse,
I'd like to see for myself.
Lady Kycilia would laugh,
but I too have my pride.
Understood, sir.
The Mad Angler will be waiting right here.
Thanks a lot, Mulligan.
I came across the Trojan Horse right after
my transfer to the Mad Angler squadron.
I am a fortunate man.
The latest report says the external repairs
should be done by tomorrow, sir.
Excellent.
I do wish I had the luxury
of giving the crew a week's rest.
Where are they now?
Sir! We've gathered them for you.
- Hey!
- Wait up!
You naughty kids! Hey!
Oh! Excuse me!
Salute to General Revil!
Neener neener!
Why, you little...!
Salute!
Good job. Please be seated.
All crew, at ease!
I don't know how I can thank you all
for your efforts since you left Side 7.
Excuse us, sir.
After receiving temporary repairs here...
...you'll go to Federation headquarters
at Jaburo, in South America.
Uh, sir?
Hm? What is it?
Yes. What about people who aren't
interested in joining the military?
You are all very capable soldiers, but...
If you decide to leave the military now,
we'd have to imprison you for at least a year.
You... You can't!
You're forcing people who don't want to...
You have all been exposed to
the military's greatest secrets.
Normally, we'd be required
to imprison you for life.
A soldier, huh...?
Moving on to a more important subject.
The Zeon Forces have recently
become quite active.
Spurred on by the appearance
of the Gundam...
...they're devoting all their resources
to the mass production of mobile suits.
Show us.
Yes, sir.
This is still unconfirmed intelligence, but...
First, the Zeons have learned
from our use of the Gundam.
There's no need for quantity
if the mobile suits are powerful enough.
They seem to feel that one or two will be
enough to obtain the desired results.
G-General! Those diagrams on the monitor!
Are they all different types of mobile suits?!
I believe so. Furthermore, Zeon is testing
a new design they call "mobile armor."
Mobile... armor?
This one Gundam has primed the pump.
Primed the pump?
The enemy's attacks will become
even fiercer. In any case...
I'll inform you of any new intelligence.
Make sure you consider
your countermeasures.
No. 2! Once you've released your Goggs,
make a detour to enter from the north!
Why don't you sink the Trojan Horse
before Captain Char arrives!?
Goggs, ready for launch!
The Goggs should reach the Trojan Horse
in about eight minutes.
We'll cover the landing of the Goggs by firing
missiles 30 seconds before they arrive.
All right, go ahead.
Man. What a hassle!
Mr. Soldier! Won't you buy something?
Huh?
There's nothing in there worth buying.
It's all locally made. And, delicious too.
You're pretty cute!
Though, it looks like you have a tough life.
Then buy something.
Maybe later.
Cheapskate!
Hey, buy something?
Ah, no.
That old man is very nice, isn't he?
You don't wanna join, Fraw Bow?
It's not that...
Good job, soldier!
If we join the military...
Who'll take care of the children?
They're all used to the White Base.
You have a point there.
Come on, kids!
It's not safe for you
here on the dock!
Go play over there!
We gotta clean all the White Base's toilets
and change the bed covers!
We got tons of things to do!
Ungrateful brats!
It would be cruel to separate them.
Okay, Marshy! We're on schedule to reach
the harbor housing the Trojan Horse!
Right!
What's this?
They're awfully small. Could they be...?!
No! Just as I feared!
Hats off to the Gogg. Not even a scratch.
Releasing Freeze Gel!
We've lost response from Area 22.
Please go to alert status.
Our approach looks problem-free.
Captain Boone!
I'm counting on your attack to cover us!
It's time... Fire missiles!
Missiles detected!
From Area 22?!
No, from 54!
What should we do?!
Well...
Which of the mobile suits
are ready to sortie?
Only the Gundam, sir.
Why not Guntank or Guncannon?!
The cannon's getting an overhaul.
The whole thing's sitting in pieces.
Amuro says he'll launch in the Gundam!
Okay.
But I heard he can't use the beam rifle.
Please check with the mechanics.
Right!
Amuro, you may proceed.
Just don't damage the dock.
Hey, come on. Fraw Bow.
You're beginning to talk like Ms. Sayla.
Oh. Really? I'm sorry.
Great. It's all going according to plan.
Chief Lasa! Marshy here.
I'm on shore, too!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
It looks like mobile suits have landed!
Don't let them near the dock!
Protect the White Base no matter what!
Do you seriously think those vulcans
will penetrate Goggs armor?
Is that also a new type of mobile suit?
It looks different from the Zakus or Goufs.
Wait, if that thing came from the sea...
...it might be the Gogg type,
which was developed to be amphibious.
There you are, mobile suit!
General. It's unsafe out here. The shelter...
No. If it's our time to die,
it makes no difference where we are.
If the commander of an army is content
to shout orders from the rear...
...he'll lose even a winning battle.
That may be true, sir, but...
Can't we defend against
attacks from the right?!
Sir! I'll pass that on.
What's happening with our defense line
from Areas 60 to 65?!
Sir! We've just requested
the Guntank's assistance!
Nowadays, everything always
comes down to mobile suits...
My, how times have changed.
The enemy is right in front of us!
Move G-Bull to Hatch 3 and send it out!
So you're saying I shouldn't be
in the G-Bull when we send it out?
Not exactly. But if you stay here for now...
...we can use the Gundam
and G-Fighter later.
A difficult choice.
Yes. Our tactics rely too much
on the Gundam.
Okay then. I'll take off in the G-Fighter.
Can't yet. The main engine still needs
a bit more work done on it.
What are you doing?!
Hurry up, will you?!
Anyway... move the G-Fighter to Deck 3
so that it's ready for takeoff.
Right!
Fraw Bow. Tell Hayato to hurry
and head out in the Guntank!
Yes, sir!
Hayato! Hayato!
Guntank, moving out!
Guntank, heading out! Open the gate for me!
Where are those missiles coming from?
White Base! Please provide some info!
That town...!
That's some mobile suit!
The vulcan guns don't seem to affect it!
But... at that speed...!
How dare you, you Gun... thingamajig!
The Gogg won't lose to your horsepower.
I-I can't believe this guy!
This hammer's been powered up, but...!
Wh-Why you!
Watch it!
Huh? What in the world are you doing
still wandering around here?
Run away, quick!
So sorry. Bye, Mr. Soldier!
Hey, we're not soldiers either!
Uh, Mr. Kai. You'd better hurry up.
Hey! Amuro! Get a move on!
If only I had the beam rifle,
I'd take out this mobile suit.
Wait a second... Fraw Bow!
Can the G-Parts be used yet?!
Let's see. Yes, they can.
Have them get the G-Bull parts ready!
Roger!
Huh? He retreated?! That Amuro!
A mobile suit that scares even the Gundam?
Mr. Omur! Please have the Gundam's
B Parts ready to launch.
You never know what'll happen in a battle!
I'm aware of that, Amuro!
Hey, Ms. Sayla!
We're taking off! Ready?
Go ahead, Amuro!
That's one unusually large tank.
Incredible...
This cockpit is so strong,
it can withstand a direct beam blast.
Go!
M... Marshy!
Damn!
Amuro. The other mobile suit
just escaped Into the sea.
Roger that!
Could you check with White Base?
Find out if the B Parts are ready.
Looks like you don't need to
return to the White Base.
Omur and the others are preparing
for a mid-air transfer.
I'm going to pilot it this time, okay Amuro?
All right, all right...
Stop! Okay, continue...
That's right! Slower!
What's wrong with the elevator?
The pressure pipe hasn't been fixed yet!
Preparations to send out
G-Armor's B Parts are complete.
Open up Central Hatch 3!
We're launching the G-Armor's B Parts.
This is very strange.
When the mobile suit vanished,
the missile bombardment stopped as well.
I see! The enemy mobile suits emerged
from the ocean, didn't they? Fraw Bow?
Yes!
Please tell Sayla to cover the Gundam with the G-Fighter!
Docking searcher synchronized! Good!
Control system is switched over!
Gundam, separating!
Roger! You need to take extra care
when pursuing the enemy, Amuro!
Roger!
Look, it's the Gundam!
It's dangerous to pursue too far...
Wh... Where is he?
Behind me!
You fell for it, Gundam!
One more shot from the beam cannons,
and you're finished!
The monitor! I can't use it!
I know!
There!
Huh? The monitor's gone out!
Wh... Who won?
Looks like the battle's over.
Amuro! Amuro! Respond!
Gundam! Gundam! Please respond!
Can't you hear the radio?
Amuro! Please... respond!
Amuro! Amuro!
Looks like the Gundam won.
Huh?
If the enemy had won,
they'd be attacking again.
Of course... it's also possible
that they destroyed each other.
I see something moving underwater!
I'll send you an image of it!
I'm receiving an image from the G-Fighter.
Connection...restored...
Can you hear me, White Base... ?
I'm returning to ship.
Mr. Bright! Amuro's on his way back now!
That's great.
He did it!
It's Captain Char!
Standby to take in his Sealance!
Wow! That's the Captain for you!
His skill is amazing!
That's it, all right. The Trojan Horse.
But... both Goggs that sent us
this video have been destroyed.
That's only to be expected.
That mobile suit isn't a
cheap mass-produced type.
Still... I am ashamed.
It's quite all right, Boone...
I can't rest until I bring this guy down...
with my own two hands.
Huh?
Yes, I know it's childish...
But that is the mobile suit
that injured my pride.
Under Char's command...
...fierce attacks on the White Base continue.
Kai Shiden's distaste for the military
leads him to say good-bye to everyone...
...but later, he rejoins the battle.
However... close behind him
is a young woman.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
A Spy on Board.
Next Time
A Spy on Board
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...